[dramatic music]
[Bonzle] Any clue
what they're saying?
How would I know?
I can't read lips.
They look upset. Why?
-Again, how would I--
-Where are they going?
They're not going...
Oh, wait, they are.
Nice! Let's give
this another shot.
[dramatic music]
Let's go, everyone.
[sighing]
You too, Wyldfyre.
Time for warm-ups.
[groans] I lost my heat power.
I've literally got
nothing to warm up with!
There's more to being a
Ninja than Elemental Powers.
Yeah, like sleeping in.
Don't ninja sleep in?
You need to focus on
learning Spinjitzu.
[grumbling]
[Riyu yawns]
I know you'll find Jay, Nya.
I have to. Even if he doesn't
remember anything about us,
Jay belongs with us.
His family.
But I'm scared, Lloyd.
He shattered his goodness.
What if he can't heal it?
There has to be a way.
And we'll all join you as
soon as the tournament ends
and we find out whoever's behind
the attacks on the dragons.
Be careful.
You too. We'll miss you.
[sighs]
I could really use my
older brother right now.
I'd do anything to hear
your voice again, Kai.
[Kai] Hello? Are you there?
Kai?
[Riyu squeals]
Riyu, did you hear him too?
[Riyu roars]
[Kai] Riyu, is someone with you?
Kai! Kai, can you hear me?
[Kai] I said, Riyu, if there's
someone there let me know!
He can't hear me?
-There must be some way to--
-[light zaps]
[Kai] We might not
have much time.
Kai?
Nya! Nya, is that you?
You have a sister
I don't know about?
How are you talking
through this stone?
"Stone"? I don't know.
I've got some of Riyu's
scales stuck to me,
so Bonzle thinks the
physical connection
lets us communicate.
Dunno why it works
with you, though.
You're my brother. We share
a lot more than a few scales.
The Forbidden Five,
four, whatever,
they're also talking to
someone on the outside.
Probably planning
something terrible.
[Nya] Great, more bad news.
Let me guess, wherever you are,
the world's in danger again?
Kai, I found Jay.
Only he's not our Jay.
He lost his memory.
It's like he's a completely
different person.
In Jay's case, that might
be an improvement. Ha!
Save the jokes till
after we free you.
Maybe this stone could do
more than allow us to speak.
It could potentially
open a doorway out.
[door bangs]
Nya, Nya, are you there?
What happened?
Nya!
♪ Lost in the unknown
So much to see ♪
♪ Together we will rise ♪
♪ We fight ♪
♪ Be a ninja for what's right ♪
[fire roars]
[yawns] It took me forever
to get back to sleep.
Every time I closed my eyes
I saw that monastery again.
Why now? Why me?
Why is it here?
Perhaps rather than
asking why you were guided
to a mysterious monastery
in the middle of the night,
a better line of inquiry might
be how you could reach it.
I need a hot bath.
-You're back.
-Arin, where've you been?
You were gone again
when we woke up.
I had stuff to think over.
[somber music]
Right, the detective work.
Did you find something
in Ras's dorm?
No. Ras caught Riyu and me.
[group gasps]
How'd you escape? Smoke bomb?
I really thought being
a Ninja would involve
way more smoke bombs.
Ras let us go.
Ras? Ras Ras?
Are we talking about
the same Ras here?
Big scary Tiger-man,
hates dragons?
He let you go?
Maybe we don't understand
his real motivation yet.
So you don't think he's
behind what happened
to the Matriarch Dragons?
Ras is the obvious suspect.
He led the Claws of the Imperium
against a Matriarch before.
But nothing connects him
to the stolen horns yet.
And don't forget,
Ras was also attacked by
a bot that first night.
Our past with Ras may have
created a confirmation bias
that blinds us to other threats.
Yeah, threats like
this ugly guy, Bleckt!
Have you seen the
way he talks to Roby?
Total villain energy.
Even his name sounds
like the sound you make
when you barf. Bleeckt!
Bleckt defeating three
Matriarch-level dragons
seems improbable.
Agree. And that's
a drawing of Zur.
Uh, if you say so.
The Devonian who beat Zane?
Why would he be a suspect?
Well, I did hear rumors
back in the Crossroads
about Devonians grinding
dragon horns into a powder
they mix with food for
strength in battle.
Dragon horns can
make you stronger,
but also fill you with rage.
Rumors and gossip
aren't evidence.
Zeatrix has been oddly confident
about winning the games.
It's like she knows
something we don't.
And she wasn't attacked by bots,
even though she drew
a lot of attention
at the banquet
earlier that night.
She definitely has
a grudge against us
for dethroning Beatrix.
Even though we totally
did her a favor.
Psh! She's super powerful
but can't control her anger.
Huh! Pathetic.
[dramatic music]
Uh, Lloyd? What do you think?
Well, Zeatrix was
once next in line
for the throne of a kingdom
that ran on Dragon Power.
If anyone knows what to do
with those horns, it's her.
Great, we have a bunch
of suspects but no proof.
Now what?
I still have one lead.
I found this symbol in the area
where the bot
attack started from.
But I have no idea
what it means.
Hey, you should check
the Temple City Museum.
Geo and I walked through there
and saw all kinds of
ancient art and writing.
Really? I'll go right away.
I could come with you.
Did that feel weird to you?
My Social Encounter
Algorithm registered
high levels of cringe.
Lloyd, can we talk about Arin?
-[gasps]
-[dramatic music]
Another vision?
I thought Rontu taught
you to control them!
This one, so strong.
I think today's the
day I fight Zeatrix.
[gasps]
And I'm going to lose.
[dramatic music]
[ominous music]
[somber music]
[dramatic music]
No, no, no.
Oops, I mean, yes,
and make sure you capture
my broad shoulders.
Arin! Whatdaya think?
I'm gonna replace these
boring old artifacts
with some bold modern art.
New and daring, like me.
The past is for dead people,
right? Can I get a stang-zoot?
I don't know.
History can be cool.
Hey, Geo.
Ugh! You sound like my uncle.
He spends hours here. And
not asleep, like you'd think.
If it were up to him, there'd be
an exhibit to watch paint dry.
Good thing ya boi's the
game Master and not him!
I see a modern,
interactive experience
with screens everywhere.
Over there, a holo-display
of the seven Source Dragons
locked in an epic battle.
Stang-zoot, right?
That does sound cool.
I mean, stoot-zang, or whatever.
Right? I don't believe any of
those old dragon myths,
but you can't beat the branding!
And this'll house
the Element Cup.
Imagine lights hitting
the glorious sheen
of its dragon ivory.
-Dragon ivory?
-Sure.
The cup is made from the
polished horn of an arc dragon.
Whoa, whoa, whoa.
Arc as in a Matriarch?
Matriarchs, Patriarchs.
Centuries ago, people
used arc dragon horns
to amplify Elemental Powers.
The cup's made of it, it's as
old as the games themselves.
Let me show you where I'll build
the VR
Experience-slash-gift shop.
Who's that?
My great, great, great,
great, you get the idea.
The tournament's
first games master.
A visionary, like me.
I'm actually wearing
his vestments.
Tailored for max
swagger, drip-drip.
Thought I'd throw my uncle a
bone with my outfit, at least.
Oops! Gotta go! The games won't
master themselves!
[dramatic music]
[gasps]
Roby, wait!
Sorry, duty calls.
[gasps]
[Arin] Could the villain
I've been looking for
this whole time be, Roby?
Has anyone seen Riyu?
He probably helped Nya leave
the city and got distracted
by all the delicious
Temple City concessions.
[dramatic music]
Elemental Masters, are
you ready to battle?
To entertain? To win?
[crowd cheering]
First up, the hard-fighting
snake who's bound
to make you shake.
It's Frak, the Elemental
Master of Quake!
-[crowd cheering]
-[sighs]
Versus a descendent
of the Devonian King,
who'll throw you
right out of the ring,
it's Zur, the Elemental
Master of Reflex!
[dramatic music]
Excuse me, Master Cole, sir.
Can I ask a question
about your Earth power?
Uh, sure, I guess.
I've been practicing
with it since our match,
but I feel resistance from
the stone I don't experience
when using my Quake energy.
You're probably trying to lift.
Earth's power comes from below.
Instead of pulling up,
reach down and push out.
[energy zapping]
Wow, I never considered
how two similar powers
could be so different.
Thank you, sir!
[Ras groans]
Are you sure it's a good idea
-to help someone on Ras' team?
-You heard what Zane said.
We can't let our past with
Ras color our judgment.
I've got a good
feeling about Frak.
Besides, isn't he Arin's friend?
[dramatic music]
[crowd cheering]
[bell tolling]
[Roby] Frak opens strong
with a Quake,
but the Master of
Reflex dodges with ease!
Uh-oh, Zur! Better look
before you leap and after.
We don't call this game
Grid Drop for nothing!
[light zapping]
If that were us up there,
the battle would
already be over.
When I was in exile,
all I had was the dream
of exacting revenge
on my sister.
You Ninja stole
that chance from me.
Seems only right to exact
that same revenge on you.
[Ras laughing]
-[groaning]
-[laughing]
This is the Legendary
Green Ninja
who dethroned my sister?
Sad.
-[dramatic music]
-[sighs]
[fist thudding]
[light zaps]
-[group gasps]
-Frak, reach down and push out!
[dramatic music]
Yeah!
[light zapping]
[crowd cheering]
[Roby] We have a winner.
[light zapping]
[crowd cheering]
How dare you seek
counsel from the enemy!
What? Master Cole?
Well, it's his power,
I just thought--
Master Cole? I am
your Master, no other.
Do you understand?
Yes, Master.
[gulping]
[coughs] Ugh!
The tea's cold and I've got
no powers to heat it with!
Not having Elemental Powers
is just the worst!
I mean, it's fine
for some people.
Not everyone is suited
for an exciting life.
Oh, hi, Arin!
Wyldfyre, what do
you think of Roby?
He's alright, I guess,
for a super cool genius
that everyone adores.
Why? Did he ask about me?
Just trying to follow the facts.
-[crowd cheering]
-[dramatic music]
-[bell tolls]
-[crowd cheering]
[dramatic music]
[bell tolling]
-Yeah! Woo-hoo!
-[cheering]
[water bubbles]
[light zapping]
[crashes]
[dramatic music]
[fireball zings]
[crowd cheering]
-[light zapping]
-[dramatic music]
[bell tolls]
[grunts] That was--
A lot.
[sighs] At least it's over.
Guess your vision about fighting
Zeatrix today was wrong.
Well, it's all over for today.
Or is it?
Wait, what? Surprise!
Ya boi planned a
secret bonus game.
[cheering]
Wow! That's what all your
minds sound like right now!
He's lean, he's green,
but he's never mean.
It's Lloyd, Elemental
Master of Life!
-[crowd cheering]
-His opponent is a former twin,
who will do anything to win.
The very angry Elemental
Master of Shockwave, Zeatrix!
Welcome to The
Gauntlet what-what?
This game's goal is simple.
Retrieve these epic
hand-to-hand weapons
and yeet your opponent
off the platform.
The sword from my vision.
Gotta get to it
before Zeatrix does.
The challengers
are free to use any
and all Elemental Powers,
but the final blow
must be executed with a
weapon from the Gauntlet.
Copy? Cool.
Ready? Set?
Go, go, go.
[bell tolls]
[fire explodes]
Lloyd's coming out hot! Ba-Bam!
-[dramatic music]
-[Lloyd grunts, groans]
Oops, maybe too strong!
Looks like Lloyd hasn't mastered
that elemental power yet!
Can't all be winners!
-[blades breaking]
-Easy breezy.
Zeatrix uses the
Elemental Power of wind.
Be sure to thank
Euphrasia later, Z!
[light zapping]
[dramatic music]
[swords clangs]
Elemental Fusion fused
those weapons! Clever move!
Look out below!
[light zapping]
Zing! Lloyd uses the
Elemental Power of Size
to duck Zeatrix's blast.
Remember, there are no small
Powers, only small masters.
Lloyd is deploying an
unusual fight strategy.
Yeah, it's not fighting.
It's running away.
[dramatic music]
And Zeatrix pulls out the
Elemental Power of Figment!
She's her own party,
but which one is real?
[blows thudding]
Your sister Beatrix didn't
need these tricks to fight me.
No, she needed an army. My army!
Gotcha.
[light zapping]
Ouch! Lloyd Ze-a-tricked her
into giving up
her real location!
[crowd cheering]
[dramatic music]
No!
[light zapping]
[dramatic music]
Blink and you miss it!
Lloyd pulls a Mr. Pale
and goes invisible.
-[light zapping]
-[dramatic music]
This could be it!
Why doesn't Lloyd knock her off?
I've got to find that
sword from my visions.
Where did you go, coward?
[dramatic music]
-[light zapping]
-There you are.
Wow! Zeatrix using Elemental
Sound to echolocate.
Folks, I've never seen and
not seen anything like this!
Seems like Zeatrix is
using the Elemental Power
of Surface Tension to fill a
bubble with shockwave energy.
She's making an Elemental Bomb!
[bomb explodes]
-[crowd cheering]
-They've broken the game!
In thousands of years, this
has never happened before!
Is my tournament wild or what?
Stang-zooot!
We need a short intermission
while bots repair the Gauntlet
from this unprecedented
intensity.
I encourage you to
visit concessions,
hear there's some amazing pies!
You're doing great, buddy.
You have already beaten the
odds by getting this far.
You're losing, Lloyd, but
not to her, to your own fear.
You're right. But how do I fight
a battle I've seen myself lose?
When I faced Cinder, you
told me not to make my fear
a self-fulfilling prophecy.
And I won.
Ninja don't fight because
we know we'll win,
we do it because some things
are worth fighting for,
no matter what the outcome is.
Maybe I should
take my own advice.
[dramatic music]
Welcome back, competitors
and spectators.
These games would be
nothing without you.
Well, they'd be just me,
which is still pretty amazing.
But I dare say, enough about me!
[dramatic music]
[bell tolls]
Zeatrix brings back the bubble!
But adding some Elemental
Wind to give herself the edge!
[bubble bursts]
Whoa! I hate to burst
her bubble,
but Lloyd
just burst her bubble!
[Lloyd] No more running.
-[dramatic music]
-[yelling]
[both grunting and yelling]
-[screaming]
-Yes!
[crowd cheering]
Lloyd is the winner!
Hey, hey, hey, stop!
The game's already over.
Lloyd, look out!
[dramatic music]
[Ras laughing]
[Lloyd crashes]
[Lloyd groans]
-[dramatic music]
-[gasping]
[Lloyd coughs, gasps]
[dramatic music plays]